<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<accomInformation xmlns="http://jvh/schemas/ws/api/3.0/feeds/accomInformation" xmlns:ns2="http://jvh/schemas/ws/api/3.0/common">
	<accommodation accomId="183">
		<arrivalDeparture>
			<arrivalKeyDetails changed="2017-07-01 14:03:00">You will find the villa key in the keybox which is situated adjacent to the entrance door. Use the following instructions to open the keybox: A) Push the following buttons in on the keybox - 1938B.  
B) Push down the OPEN button and whilst holding it down pull the lid out from the keybox. If you have entered the wrong combination, you can return the buttons to their original setting by sliding down the CLEAR button. 
C) When you release the OPEN button the combination will clear. 
D) To replace the lid push in the buttons 1938B and place the lid into the keybox by setting the bottom of the lid into the vault. Then push down and hold the OPEN button as you return the lid to the closed position. The lid will lock into place and the combination will clear when the OPEN button is released.  Please only use the key box on arrival and departure, it is not designed for on-going use.</arrivalKeyDetails>
			<departureKeyDetails changed="2017-02-20 15:24:00">On the morning of departure please leave the villa key in the key box.</departureKeyDetails>
		</arrivalDeparture>
		<directions>
			<villaDirections changed="2017-01-24 14:42:00">• As you leave the airport car park keep in the right hand lane and follow signs to Yaiza/Playa Blanca.

• Follow the road under the dual carriageway and you will be filtered on to the dual carriageway that you have just gone underneath, this is the LZ-2. 

• Continue on this road climbing the hill, don’t turn off for Puerto del Carmen. The road you are on will run past the village of Tias and then filter into single lane traffic on your way to La/Asomada/Macher. Keep on the left hand lane and this will filter you on to the direct road to Macher.

• At the first roundabout you approach, take the first exit on the right , a short way along this road you will approach a second roundabout, take the second exit (straight ahead). 

• Approximately 20 metres after the roundabout, take the first turning on your right, just after the Bus Stop.

• Villa Pedro is the last house on the left, it is surrounded by a volcanic stone wall.

On your return to Arrecife airport, 
On your return to Arrecife airport, take the LZ-2 following signs for the airport. Take the exit for Terminal 1, if you are returning your hire car, follow signs for Departures (Salidas) and then enter the left-hand filter lane sign posted Hertz and park in the allocated return parking to return your hire cars. Return the keys to the small white car hire office then make your way to the departure lounge on the 1st floor.


        
</villaDirections>
		</directions>
		<villaBook>
			<atm changed="2017-06-27 13:47:00">The nearest banks and ATMs can be found in Puerto del Carmen on Calle Reina Sofia. There is an ATM at the petrol station around the corner from the property, at the Macher roundabout.</atm>
			<bakery changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Bakeries can be found in the nearby village of Tias, the 'Horno del Pan' is located on Avenida Central or the 'San Antonio' bakery is located on Calle Libertad.</bakery>
			<bank changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">The nearest Bank  is situated in Puerto del Carmen.
On the main roundabout where the EuroSpar is located follow the sign for Puerto del Carmen. Follow this road right down to the second roundabout where you take the last exit down to the left and follow the road down the hill onto Calle Reina Sofia. The bank ‘La Caixa’ is situated on the left hand side of the road.
Please note that banks no longer offer money exchange if you don’t have an account with them.</bank>
			<bbq changed="2017-04-07 13:39:00">Please only use coal on the BBQ. Always ensure that the BBQ is never left unattended once lit and until all the ashes have cooled. Please place your cold ash in a rubbish bag and take to the bins. Please leave the barbecue and utensils clean after use for future guests.

</bbq>
			<beach changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Playa Grande – Puerto del Carmen This long sandy beach is the main beach in Puerto del Carmen, and one of the most popular on the Island. Sun beds and parasols are available to hire for a small fee and has amenities such as first aid facilities, toilets and showers. 

Playa Chica – Old Town Puerto del Carmen: Located next to the small pier in the old town ‘Playa Chica’ is a sandy beach where you can try out many of the water sports such as Parascending, Jetski and banana ski bus. This small bay is host to a diving school and is a great place for children to try out some snorkelling. 
</beach>
			<busStop changed="2017-02-24 11:25:00">The nearest bus is located just a 4-5 minute walk from the property.  Walk to the end of the lane and take left onto the main road.  There are stops on either side of the road.</busStop>
			<church changed="2017-02-24 11:25:00">The Roman Catholic Church of San Antonio de Padua is located on Avenida Central in Tias, weekly services are held Saturday evenings at 7pm.</church>
			<doctor changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Please remember to take your passport and medical insurance with you. It is important that you speak to your insurance company before visiting a private clinic to check that your insurance covers you for your visit. Please note that you may need to pay the excess. Private Clinic The International Clinic in Puerto del Carmen is located on Calle Acatife No. 9. Opening Hours: everyday 09.00 – 20.00. Tel &amp; Emergency No. (0034) 928 511082. 

Centro de Salud Tias - State Doctors clinic Please note that to use this service you with need an in-date EHIC – European Health Insurance Card which will entitle you to state healthcare you will also need to take your passport with you. You may need a translator to use this service. Located on Avenida Central, Tias – situated on the main high street in the centre of Tias.  Opening Hours: 08.00 – 20.00 hrs Monday – Friday. 09.00 – 14.00 hrs Saturdays and bank holidays. Emergencies open 24 hrs daily. Tel (0034) 928 524440 or 928 524244. Please remember to take your passport and EHIC (European Health Card – formally known as E111 form). Please note, they may not speak your language. EHIC is not an alternative to travel insurance because it does not cover the costs of private healthcare or services that are not part of the state healthcare system, nor does it cover the cost of being taken home.
</doctor>
			<fuseBox changed="2017-02-24 11:26:00">The fuse box is located to the right the front door; above TV area.   If the main fuse has blown it is advised to lower all of the switches, push the main switch upwards then one by one, the rest of the fuses in the box.  If the power trips again whilst doing this then start again and do not touch the one that tripped. Please call your Villa Manager to report this so that a technician can be called.</fuseBox>
			<hob changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Press the far left button to turn on electricity on hob.
Select the required hob by pressing the button with the four hob symbol until the required hob ring lights up.
Press the plus and minus button for selected temperature and time.</hob>
			<hospital changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">The nearest private hospital is the Hospiten. Located in Lomo Gordo on the LZ-40 at the rear of Puerto del Carmen. Tel: 0034 928 596 100. Please remember to take your passport and medical insurance with you. It is important that you speak to your insurance company before visiting a private hospital to check that your insurance covers you for your visit. Please note that you may need to pay the excess. 

The nearest state-provided hospital is Hospital Doctor Jose Molina Orosa. Located on Carretera San Bartolome in Arrecife. Tel: 0034 928 595 000. 

Please remember to take your passport and EHIC (European Health Card – formally known as E111 form). Please note, they may not speak your language. EHIC is not an alternative to travel insurance because it does not cover the costs of private healthcare or services that are not part of the state healthcare system, nor does it cover the cost of being taken home. In the event of an emergency dial 112, Calls are free and attended to quickly and in your own language. The Service at this number co-ordinates all calls to ambulances, fire brigade and security forces to ensure the most rapid and most effective response to any emergency.

</hospital>
			<lastDay changed="2017-04-07 13:39:00">Prices and availability range due to limited amenities, if you are interested in booking a last day facility, please speak to your Villa Manager for further information as luggage storage/day rooms are always subject to availability.</lastDay>
			<lights changed="2017-02-24 11:33:00">Please turn off all the lights before you go to bed as they will attract unwanted insects and mosquitoes.</lights>
			<maidService changed="2017-03-22 14:49:00">A change of towels will be provided half way through your holiday.

If you are holidaying with us for more than one week, a full clean and change of linen and towels will be provided at the start of each week of your holiday.  If you are holidaying with us for 10 or 11 nights you will receive this service on day 5 or 6 of your holiday.</maidService>
			<markets changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Puerto del Carmen Market. Location: Plaza del Varadero held in the square in the harbour of Puerto Del Carmen This market offers souvenirs and crafts surrounded by the pleasant atmosphere of the Old Towns many bars and restaurants. Held every Friday between 10.00 and 15.00.</markets>
			<outdoorFurnishings changed="2017-02-24 11:33:00">Please place your towels on the sun loungers to protect them from sun cream and wet clothing.  Please put any soft furnishings under cover in the evening or when it’s raining.  Please close the umbrella after use, and lay it flat in windy weather conditions.</outdoorFurnishings>
			<oven changed="2017-05-30 17:57:00">To operate the oven select the desired cooking function using the dial on the left. The dial to the right is to set the temperature.</oven>
			<petrolStation changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">The nearest petrol station is located on the LZ-2.  Drive back on to the main road from the lane and take the left turning. Take the second exit at the roundabout. At the next roundabout take the first exit.  The petrol station is located on the right hand side of the road.</petrolStation>
			<pharmacy changed="2017-02-25 14:26:00">The nearest Pharmacy is located in Puerto del Carmen.  Drive straight down to the roundabout with Euro Spar situated on the left &amp; take the second exit.  At the next roundabout go straight and then take the second turning on your right.  In Spain a pharmacy is called a farmacia. They are identified by a green cross outside the building.
In each resort there is always one pharmacy open 24 hours, time table details are on all pharmacy doors.</pharmacy>
			<policeStation changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">The Guardia Civil police station is located on Calle Manguia, Puerto del Carmen, next to the Biosfera shopping Centre. Tel: 0034 928 516 111.   They are open 24 hours, 7 days a week. Please note a translator may be required.</policeStation>
			<pool changed="2017-02-24 11:46:00">Pools are cleaned on a regular basis and chemicals added. Please try to avoid sand getting into the pool as this can block the filters. Sun creams and oils can make the water cloudy and dirty and leave a residue on the side of the pool. Therefore, please do not enter the pool directly after applying sun lotions.  We kindly ask you to shower before entering the pool. 
Pool heating is in operation during Winter months. The pool is heated and is designed to warm the water not make the water hot. The temperature of the pool will also depend on the weather conditions if a pool cover is available, it must be used when the pool is not in use and overnight to help maintain the pool temperature.</pool>
			<poolPumps changed="2017-02-24 11:46:00">The pool pump is on an automatic timer, it is set to run for different lengths of times throughout a 24 hour period.</poolPumps>
			<powerWaterCuts changed="2017-02-24 11:46:00">If you suffer from a power or water cut please first check the fuse box (See Fuse box information).  Fridge/freezers keep their temperature for many hours without power if the doors are kept closed. Please call your villa manager if the electric or water does not return.   They will be able to check if the problem localised or if there is a problem in your villa.</powerWaterCuts>
			<restaurantsBars changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">You will find some local restaurants and bars in El Puerto, Old Town Harbour and along the main promenade of Avenida de las Playas. Try heading to Puerto Calero Marina only a 5 minute drive or taxi ride from the villa.
</restaurantsBars>
			<safe changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Your safe is located in the wardrobe of the double en suite bedroom</safe>
			<satellite changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Use the Sony remote to switch on the TV by pressing the power button.
Switch on the satellite by pressing the standby button on grey remote.
Using the grey satellite remote select the channel using the TV R button.
</satellite>
			<smoking changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">Please note this is a No Smoking villa. Please smoke outside in the villa grounds and use the ashtrays provided.</smoking>
			<supermarket changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">The nearest supermarket is located on the large Macher roundabout next to the petrol station. The EuroSpar Supermarket is open Monday – Saturday 08:00 – 22:00.

</supermarket>
			<taxis changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">The nearest taxi rank is located in Puerto del Carmen by the bank on Calle Reina Sofia. Puerto del Carmen taxi service number is 0034 928 524 220. Alternatively you can flag down a taxi on the street.</taxis>
			<tv-dvd changed="2017-02-24 11:55:00">To operate the TV press the power button on the Sony remote control.  Use the grey remote for the satellite system, select TV press in the TV R button.  Channel list:  CCTV1 – BBC1, CCTV2 – BBC2, CCTV3 – ITV1, CCTV4 – CHANNEL 4, CCTV5 – CHANNEL 5, CCTV6 – RTE1, CCTV7 – RTE2, CCTV8 – TV3, CCTV9 – CBBC – BBC3, CCTV10 – CBEENIES – BBC4, CCTV11 – ITV2, CCTV12 – ITV3.</tv-dvd>
			<washingMachine changed="2017-02-24 11:55:00">To operate the washing machine select the wash programme by turning the centre dial  Press the Inicio/start button on the right for the cycle to start.   Delicado – Delicate, Lana – Wool, Pre lavado – pre wash, Sinteticos – Synthetics.  Please remember to wait approximately 5 minutes after the cycle has stopped before opening the door, this enables the safety mechanism to turn off.  Please do not open before this time as it may result in the door becoming damaged.</washingMachine>
			<wasteDisposal changed="2017-02-24 11:55:00">The rubbish is collected daily with the exception of Sundays and bank holidays.  The closest waste and recycling bins to your villa can be found by heading back to the main road, turn left and head to the roundabout, the containers are located on the right.  GREEN – Bottles, YELLOW – Plastics and carton, BLUE - Paper.  Please remove all rubbish from the villa daily; due to the hot climate rubbish may attract unwanted visitors.</wasteDisposal>
			<water changed="2017-06-27 13:47:00">We advise against drinking the tap water as it may contain minerals that you're not used to and may therefore cause stomach upset. Bottled water can be purchased from supermarkets and petrol stations inexpensively.</water>
			<wifi changed="2017-05-30 17:50:00">WiFi is available in your villa.
Network -  HUAWEI _ B310 – 87FE.
Password – 9HLR5AFY2LE.
Due to the type of internet provided at this property, we ask you to please not download books/films and to refrain from using streaming services; as this will use all the data from the maximum monthly allowance from the internet service provider.</wifi>
			<windowsDoorsShutters changed="2017-06-27 13:47:00">Please ensure shutters, windows, and doors are closed and locked when going out or by the pool.</windowsDoorsShutters>
		</villaBook>
		<contacts changed="2016-01-28 16:53:00">
			<contact type="Rep" name="Jennie Andrews" telephone="0034 619 604640"/>
			<contact type="Rep" name="Kate Knight" telephone="0034 606 283 968"/>
		</contacts>
	</accommodation>
	<accommodation accomId="3393">
		<arrivalDeparture>
			<arrivalKeyDetails changed="2013-05-17 14:02:00">On arrival your villa key will be in the key box located to the left of the front door, the code is 8270</arrivalKeyDetails>
		</arrivalDeparture>
		<directions>
			<villaDirections changed="2014-06-05 15:28:00">At the exit of the airport, turn left at the traffic lights, heading in the direction of Rhodes Town.

At the next traffic lights, turn right. You are now heading from the west of the island, over to the east.

Follow this road to the end, going straight ahead at the traffic lights,at the crossroads.

At the end of this road, turn right at the traffic lights, heading south down the dual carriageway,
 in the direction of Lindos.

You will continue along this road passing through Faliraki, Afandou, Kolumbia and Tsambika.

At the roundabout in Archangelos take the second exit continuing to head south in the direction
 of Lindos.

At the Haraki roundabout, again take the second exit, following the signpost for Lindos.

At the Massari roundabout, it is again the second exit, continuing south.

After passing through the village of Kalathos you will pass the large supermarket,Flevari’s, to your right.

At the roundabout here take the second exit for Lindos.

You will pass above Lindos Bay to your left and you will soon see the village of Lindos and the Acropolis to your left.

Stay along the top road, passing by Lindos and carry on following the signs for Pefkos.

Following this road you will pass through Psalto with the sea to your left, and then you will go up a steep hill,with a sharp bend, bringing you out into the resort of Pefkos.

Take the 2nd left,passing by the Bakery of Pefkos, and continue to the bottom of the hill.

At the crossroads,with Caprice Bar to your right, turn left along the main road of Pefkos.

Keep on this road, passing by Fokia Bay. You will see a notice on your right marking a military area.

Continue up to your left, passing the sign for Seaview Villas, at the childrens play area follow the road round to the right. Ahead of you are the 7 villas that make up Pefkos Horizons.

Turn left at the electric box, with the private road sign.

Villa Artemis is the second villa on the right.


</villaDirections>
		</directions>
		<villaBook>
			<atm changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">When exiting the villas main gate you turn right on the main road and continue for 2.4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, turn left and after 100 metres you will see on your right Flevaris super market which has an ATM machine.</atm>
			<bakery changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2.4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, turn left and after 100 metres you will see on your right Flevaris super market which has a bakery section in.</bakery>
			<bank changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Exit the villas main gate turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, turn left and after 1km you turn left on the traffic lights where the sign says Afantou Village. Continue straight for 1.2 km towards to the cente eof the village where you can find two Banks.</bank>
			<beach changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, you continue straight towards Kolymbia and after 2km you are at Kolymbia beach.There is also one of the best beaches in Rhodes ‘Tsampika beach’ which is located by turning right at the traffic lights and continue for 1.5km</beach>
			<busStop changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, turn left and after 100 metres you will see on your right the bus station going to Rhodes town. Alternatively by turning right after 50 metres you will come across the bus station going to Lindos.</busStop>
			<doctor changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, you continue straight towards to Kolymbia. After 2km you will reach Kolymbia where the doctor’s office is located. Alternatively there is a Clinic in Archagelos Village which is located: Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights you turn right and after a 5.2km the medical center is on the left of the main road.</doctor>
			<hospital changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">The nearest private hospital can be found by exiting the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights you turn right and after a 5.2km the medical center is on the left of the main road. Please remember to take your passport and medical insurance with you. It is important that you speak to your insurance company before visiting a private hospital to check that your insurance covers you for your visit. Please note that you may need to pay the excess. 
</hospital>
			<lastDay changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">The management company will meet you on your last day and assist you with any cases you might have.</lastDay>
			<lights changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">The pool and garden lights are automatic with a timer.</lights>
			<markets changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">There are two Super markets 2.5km away from the villas. Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2.4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, turn left and after 100 metres you will see on your right Flevaris super market.</markets>
			<outdoorFurnishings changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">Please place your towels on the sun loungers to protect them from sun cream and wet clothing. Please put any soft furnishings under cover in the evening or when it’s raining. Please close the umbrella after use, and lay it flat in windy weather conditions.

</outdoorFurnishings>
			<petrolStation changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">There are two Super markets 2.5km away from the villas. Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2.4 km. Once you are at the main roads traffic lights, turn left and after 400 meters you will see on your right a Petrol Station.</petrolStation>
			<pharmacy changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2.4 km. Once you are at the main road traffic lights, continue straight towards Kolymbia and after 2km you are at Kolymbia area where a Pharmacy on your right</pharmacy>
			<policeStation changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. Once you are at the main road traffic lights turn right and after a 5.2km you enter Archangelos village (on your right). Continue a further 200 metres and then on your right you will find the police station.</policeStation>
			<restaurantsBars changed="2017-04-27 15:11:00">Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2,4 km. On your left there are two restaurants. For bars you have to continue another 2km in Kolymbia area. 
</restaurantsBars>
			<smoking changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">Please note this is a Non-Smoking villa. Please smoke outside in the villa grounds and use the ashtrays provided.</smoking>
			<supermarket changed="2017-04-28 09:15:00">There are two Super markets 2.5km away from the villas. Exit the villas main gate and turn right on the main road and continue for 2.4 km. Once you are at the main road traffic lights, turning left and after 100 metres you will see on your right Flevaris super market.</supermarket>
		</villaBook>
		<contacts changed="2017-01-10 00:00:00">
			<contact type="Management Company" name="Charlie Lee (LPM)" telephone="0030 22440 31650" additionalTelephone="0030 6945383195"/>
			<contact type="Management Company 24H" name="Ivan Pander (LPM)" telephone="0030 22440 31650" additionalTelephone="0030 6945383195"/>
		</contacts>
	</accommodation>
</accomInformation>